export const questions = {
  english: [
    {
      questionid: 1,
      question:
        "Which of the following is used in React.js to increase performance?",
      questiontype: "radio",
      correctAns: "Virtual DOM",
      questionoption: [
        {
          optionid: 11,
          optionvalue: "Virtual DOM",
        },
        {
          optionid: 12,
          optionvalue: "Original DOM",
        },
        {
          optionid: 13,
          optionvalue: "Both A and B",
        },
        {
          optionid: 14,
          optionvalue: "None of the above",
        },
      ],
    },
    {
      questionid: 2,
      question:
        "State whether true or false:  Props are methods into other components?",
      questiontype: "radio",
      correctAns: "True",
      questionoption: [
        {
          optionid: 21,
          optionvalue: "True",
        },
        {
          optionid: 22,
          optionvalue: "False",
        },
      ],
    },
    {
      questionid: 3,
      question:
        "Fill in the blank:\nI only have to _______ my head above water one more week",
      questiontype: "radio",
      correctAns: "keep",
      questionoption: [
        {
          optionid: 31,
          optionvalue: "reserve",
        },
        {
          optionid: 32,
          optionvalue: "keep",
        },
        {
          optionid: 33,
          optionvalue: "guarantee",
        },
        {
          optionid: 34,
          optionvalue: "promise",
        },
      ],
    },
    {
      questionid: 4,
      question: `Match the following.`,
      matchoptions: [
        "A. Bolometer ------- 1.	Reflection coefficients ",
        "B.	VSWR meter ------- 2.	Half power beam widths",
        "C.	Cavity wave meter ------- 3. Microwave power",
        "D.	Pattern recorder ------- 4. Microwave frequency",
      ],
      correctAns: "A-3, B-1, C-4, D-2",
      questiontype: "radio",
      questionoption: [
        {
          optionid: 41,
          optionvalue: "A-2, B-1, C-4, D-3",
        },
        {
          optionid: 42,
          optionvalue: "A-3, B-1, C-4, D-2",
        },
        {
          optionid: 43,
          optionvalue: "A-2, B-4, C-1, D-3",
        },
        {
          optionid: 44,
          optionvalue: "A-3, B-4, C-1, D-2",
        },
      ],
    },
    {
      questionid: 5,
      question:
        "By the meteorological calendar, which 3 months are a part of summer in the northern hemisphere.",
      correctAns: ["June", "July", "August"],
      questiontype: "checkbox",
      questionoption: [
        {
          optionid: 51,
          optionvalue: "June",
        },
        {
          optionid: 52,
          optionvalue: "July",
        },
        {
          optionid: 53,
          optionvalue: "August",
        },
        {
          optionid: 54,
          optionvalue: "May",
        },
        {
          optionid: 55,
          optionvalue: "Spetember",
        },
      ],
    },
  ],
  hindi: [
    {
      questionid: 1,
      question: "भारतीय उपमहाद्वीप मूलतः एक अंग था ?",
      questiontype: "radio",
      correctAns: "गोंडवाना लैण्ड का",
      questionoption: [
        {
          optionid: 11,
          optionvalue: "जुरैस्सिक लैण्ड का",
        },
        {
          optionid: 12,
          optionvalue: "गोंडवाना लैण्ड का",
        },
        {
          optionid: 13,
          optionvalue: "आर्यवर्त लैण्ड का",
        },
        {
          optionid: 14,
          optionvalue: "अंगार लैण्ड का",
        },
      ],
    },
    {
      questionid: 2,
      question: "रोम एक वोलेटाइल मेमोरी के अंतर्गत आती है?",
      questiontype: "radio",
      correctAns: "गलत",
      questionoption: [
        {
          optionid: 21,
          optionvalue: "सही",
        },
        {
          optionid: 22,
          optionvalue: "गलत",
        },
      ],
    },
    {
      questionid: 3,
      question:
        "सही विकल्प से रिक्त स्थान की पूर्ति कीजिए। : \n___________ एक ऐसा व्यक्ति जो मानव जाति से नफरत करता है",
      questiontype: "radio",
      correctAns: "मिसन्थरापे",
      questionoption: [
        {
          optionid: 31,
          optionvalue: "मस्सिआह",
        },
        {
          optionid: 32,
          optionvalue: "मिसायनिस्ट",
        },
        {
          optionid: 33,
          optionvalue: "सैडिस्ट",
        },
        {
          optionid: 34,
          optionvalue: "मिसन्थरापे",
        },
      ],
    },
    {
      questionid: 4,
      question: `सुमेलित करो`,
      matchoptions: [
        "A. बर्ड मेन ऑफ इंडिया ------- 1.सुश्रुत ",
        "B.	मिसाइल मैन ------- 2.डॉ एपीजे अब्दुल कलाम ",
        "C.	प्लास्टिक सर्जरी के पिता ------- 3. डॉ भाभा",
        "D.	भारतीय परमाणु विज्ञान के पिता ------- 4. डॉ सलीम अली",
      ],
      correctAns: "A-4, B-2, C-1, D-3",
      questiontype: "radio",
      questionoption: [
        {
          optionid: 41,
          optionvalue: "A-4, B-2, C-1, D-3",
        },
        {
          optionid: 42,
          optionvalue: "A-3, B-1, C-4, D-2",
        },
        {
          optionid: 43,
          optionvalue: "A-2, B-4, C-1, D-3",
        },
        {
          optionid: 44,
          optionvalue: "A-3, B-4, C-1, D-2",
        },
      ],
    },
    {
      questionid: 5,
      question: "इनमे से कौन पालतू जानवर हैं?",
      correctAns: ["गाय", "बिल्ली", "कुत्ता"],
      questiontype: "checkbox",
      questionoption: [
        {
          optionid: 51,
          optionvalue: "गाय",
        },
        {
          optionid: 52,
          optionvalue: "बिल्ली",
        },
        {
          optionid: 53,
          optionvalue: "शेर",
        },
        {
          optionid: 54,
          optionvalue: "कुत्ता",
        },
        {
          optionid: 55,
          optionvalue: "लोमड़ी",
        },
      ],
    },
  ],
};
